

CHRISTOPHE THIEBAUD

HEBELSTRASSE 2, HOCKENHEIM, 68766, GERMANY +49 176 81 20 33 24 CHRISTOPHE.THIEBAUD@AEQUOLOGICA.NET

I have been developing software since 1987, filling a number of different roles including Architect, People Manager, Project Manager, Lead Developer and Outside Advisor. What energizes me? A challenging position where I am able to build on decades of experience in the **creativity** + **technical expertise** + **people ecology** magical bundle to deliver truly beautiful software.

I am actively looking for a position in either **France**, or **Italy**, or ... both ©











EXPERIENCE

ARCHITECT

SAP. WALLDORF. GERMANY

Hard skills: Anything prefixed with "cloud"; DevOps; Microservices; Git; Jenkins; Docker; Continuous Deployment.

Soft skills: Internal Trainer (Continuous Integration & DevOps course); Agile Processes & Scrum.

November 2010 - Present

MANAGER

BUSINESS OBJECTS, PARIS, FRANCE

Hard skills: REST API design; System Performance Management.

Soft skills: Managing People; rolling out engineering processes and tools, worldwide.

February 2005 - November 2010

TEAM LEAD

UNIMATICA, BOLOGNA, ITALY

Hard skills: Linux; Digital Signature; Java; Javascript; HTTP & HTML & CSS; Web Servers (Tomcat & Websphere); Maven; XML.

Soft skills: Web UI Design; Using and contributing to open source software.

January 2000 - February 2005

CONSULTANT

SELF-EMPLOYED, BOLOGNA, ITALY

Hard skills: Graph Algorithms; Game Programming; Macintosh Programming.

Soft skills: Selling myself; Selling one same software component to multiple customers.

September 1995 - January 2000

PROJECT MANAGER

EUROLOG, MUNICH, GERMANY

Hard skills: n/a.

Soft skills: Juggling with external contractors; Juggling with internal politics.

July 1993 - July 1995

CODER

DATAID & COMELOG (SOFTWARE HOUSES), PARIS, FRANCE

Hard skills: Windows & OS/2 SDKs; C & C++; Relational Databases & SQL; System Integration.

Soft skills: Humility (being sold to customers as OOP guru); Team Lead.

July 1987 - July 1993

SUPPORT TECHNICIAN

ISI (HARDWARE RESELLER), PARIS, FRANCE

Hard skills: Everything (answering a wild variety of questions at the hot-line).

Soft skills: The Customer Is Always Right.

June 1986 - July 1987

EDUCATION

INSEAD, FONTAINEBLEAU, FRANCE

MBA

Finance

January 1992 - December 1992

ÉCOLE NORMALE DE MUSIQUE DE PARIS

DIPLÔME D'EXÉCUTION

Guitar

September 1978 - June 1982

LYCÉE POINCARÉ, NANCY, FRANCE

CLASSES PRÉPARATOIRES AUX GRANDES ECOLES

Mathématiques supérieures

September 1977 - June 1978

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES & TOOLS











PROCESSES

- ✓ Multi-cultural environment
- ✓ Agile Development & Scrum

LANGUAGES

- French, mother tongue
- English, fluent
- 1 Italian, fluent
- & German, basic

INTERESTS



In addition to being a geek, I am a fine guitar player, with a strong focus on JS Bach music (google for

Thiebaud+Bach).



ॐ BIKE

~ 4000 kms per year, mostly commuting.



FAVOURITE QUOTES

- $^{\rm w}$ Why program by hand in 5 days what you can spend 5 years of your life automating ? $^{\rm w}$ Terence Parr
- « So convenient a thing it is to be a reasonable creature, since it enables one to find or make a reason for everything one has a mind to do. »

Benjamin Franklin

- $\label{eq:control_control} \mbox{$^{\prime}$ Triple-double-quoted strings, with the addition that they are multiline, like the triple-single-quoted strings. $^{\prime}$ }$
- Groovy programming language documentation
- « Without the ball, you can't win. » Johan Cruyff

AWARDS & CERTIFICATIONS

Y Business Objects Leadership Award

Business Objects Product Group Recognition of Leadership Awarded to: Christophe Thiebaud For demonstrating exceptional leadership and making a difference, taking responsibility and setting the right example. You encourages others to give their opinions, supports their ideas but don't hesitate to raise questions, and explore news ways to get the job done, even if it means more work for you. Congratulations Christophe! Business Objects *Making BI Everyone's Everyday Tool* December 06, 2007

Proud to be a jgrapht contributor (google for thiebaud+jgrapht).

